fraserinstitute.org 2019-06-19

# Privacy Policy | Fraser Institute

The Fraser Institute respects the personal information privacy of users of our websites, online resources and surveys. We understand the need for secure handling and storage of such information, and our policies and procedures are in compliance with Canada’s Anti-Spam Law (CASL) and the EU General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR).

This privacy policy describes the types of information we may collect from you or that you may provide when you visit our online resources, and our practices for collecting, using, protecting and disclosing that information.

We may include on our websites features or links that allow you to interact with or connect to websites or other online resources of third parties. This privacy policy applies only to Fraser Institute’s websites and online resources and surveys.

 **1\. User Agreement**  
By using these websites, or our online resources, or participating in our surveys, you signify your consent to and agreement to be bound by these terms, practices and policy.

 **2\. Scope**  
This policy applies to all Fraser Institute websites, online resources, and surveys.

 **3\. Accountability**  
If you have any questions or concerns regarding our privacy policy please address them in writing to [privacy@fraserinstitute.org](mailto:privacy@fraserinstitute.org), or by mail to Fraser Institute, 4th Floor, 1770 Burrard Street, Vancouver, BC, V6J 3G7.

 **4\. Consent**  
The FRASER INSTITUTE only collects personal information from users if that user voluntarily provides us with such information by subscribing to our Email updates, registering for events, becoming a supporter of the Fraser Institute, participating in our surveys, or by submitting a question or comment to the FRASER INSTITUTE. Users are under no obligation to provide us with this information and may access our website without providing any personal information. By volunteering this information users agree to its collection for the purposes stated below.

 **5\. Children and Privacy**  
The Fraser Institute's websites do not contain content that is reasonably considered unsuitable for children.

 **6\. Purpose**  
The FRASER INSTITUTE uses the personal information collected for the following purposes:

  * To provide users with Email updates (if requested) of events, new research, and activities of the Fraser Institute.
  * To keep aggregate information on website use.
  * To obtain user feedback on the website.

 **7\. Collection of Information**  
When a user subscribes to receive Email updates from the FRASER INSTITUTE we may collect some (or all) of the following personal information:

  * Name
  * Address
  * Email address
  * Job Title (if applicable)
  * Organization (if applicable)
  * Organization Address (if applicable)
  * University/College/School name (if applicable)
  * Graduation Year (if applicable)

When a user registers for an event, or joins the Institute, some (or all) of the following personal information is collected:

  * Name
  * Address
  * Phone/Fax number
  * Email address
  * Credit Card Number, Type and Expiry Date
  * Job Title
  * Organization
  * Organization Address
  * Organization General Info
  * University/College/School name
  * Graduation Year

When submitting a comment by email to the FRASER INSTITUTE'S general mailbox **[info@fraserinstitute.org](mailto:info@fraserinstitute.org?subject=Privacy-Policy-collection-of-information "Privacy policy - collection of information")** the following personal information is collected:

  * Email address

The FRASER INSTITUTE also collects non-personally identifiable information that becomes available as a result of a user's visit to the FRASER INSTITUTE'S website. This information includes the following:

  * Log Files, which may collect information such as Internet protocol (IP) address, browser type, geographic location, Internet Service Provider (ISP), referring/exit pages, operating system, clickstream data.
  * Non-personal information about a user's visiting habits MAY also be automatically collected through the use of "[cookies](http://www.allaboutcookies.org/)."
  * The Fraser Institute websites use Google Analytics, to collect information about your online activities for non-advertising purposes. To learn more about how Google Analytics collects and processes data, please visit <https://policies.google.com/technologies/partner-sites?hl=en>.

 **8\. Limiting Use, Disclosure & Retention**  
An individual's personal information is only used in connection with the purposes identified in paragraph 4 of this policy. Individual information collected by the FRASER INSTITUTE will not be sold or made available to third parties. The retention periods for personal information collected by the FRASER INSTITUTE are as follows:

  * Information collected for the purpose of providing Email updates is retained until the user requests to be removed from our subscription list.
  * Information collected pursuant to event registrations, and memberships is retained as long as required by the Canada Customs and Revenue Agency for tax and audit purposes.

 **9\. Ensuring Accuracy**  
Users can [subscribe/opt-in](https://www.fraserinstitute.org/subscribe "subscribe") to receive Email updates from the FRASER INSTITUTE and email [privacy@fraserinstitute.org](mailto:privacy@fraserinstitute.org) to unsubscribe/opt-out from the FRASER INSTITUTE'S Email updates list at any time.

 **10\. Safeguards**  
To ensure the protection of personal information collected by us, the FRASER INSTITUTE employs the following physical, organizational and technological security safeguards:

  * Access is restricted to the FRASER INSTITUTE offices to employees and authorized individuals of the FRASER INSTITUTE only.
  * Access to the FRASER INSTITUTE server containing personal information is limited to designated employees of the FRASER INSTITUTE, our web site development company, and ISP and is accessed by use of a password.
  * The FRASER INSTITUTE server contains firewall protection. Further, all the FRASER INSTITUTE employees are made aware of the importance of maintaining the confidentiality of our users' personal information.

 **11\. Openness**  
The FRASER INSTITUTE is committed to making readily available to individuals information on our policies and practices.

 **12\. Individual Access**  
To review your personal information collected by the FRASER INSTITUTE, please direct your request in writing to [privacy@fraserinstitute.org](mailto:privacy@fraserinstitute.org), or by mail to Fraser Institute, 4th Floor, 1770 Burrard Street, Vancouver, BC, V6J 3G7.

 **13\. Challenging the FRASER INSTITUTE'S Compliance**  
If you wish to challenge the FRASER INSTITUTE'S compliance with the Personal Information Protection and Electronic Documents Act, Canada’s Anti-Spam Law (CASL), and the EU General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR) please address your concerns in writing to [privacy@fraserinstitute.org](mailto:privacy@fraserinstitute.org), or by mail to Fraser Institute, 4th Floor, 1770 Burrard Street, Vancouver, BC, V6J 3G7. If you are not satisfied with our response to your challenge, you may submit a complaint to your relevant national authority (in Canada, this is the Office of the Privacy Commissioner of Canada). Please be aware relevant authorities have time limits for the lodging of such complaints, and that appeals to the decisions of such national authorities may be possible, depending upon jurisdiction.
